PLUS M ENTERTAINMENT presents
a HIVE MEDIA CORP production
Executive Producer HONG JEONGIN
Produced by KIM WON-KUK
This film is inspired by actual events
however characters and situations have
been fictionalized for dramatic purposes.
Did war break out?
Excuse me.
General.
Col. Kang, what's going on?
I'm not sure either.
We're not under attack?
No, the front lines are fine.
This way.
The Prime Minister's here.
- What's going on?
- Later, sir.
A short time ago,
President Park passed away.
Let us offer a silent tribute and
open an emergency Cabinet meeting.
OCTOBER 26, 1979
PRESIDENT PARK ASSASSINATED
As appointed by the acting President,
I'm the new martial law commander.
The investigation into the shooting
will be led by General Chun
of Defense Security Command.
"To change the world..."
is that why you killed him?
Did you want to become
president so much?
No, how many times must I say it?
Did you think it'd work?
Did you go see a fortune teller?
Look outside. Nothing has changed.
The world is the same.
The dictator of 18 years was gone.
But the hoped-for new era did not come.
Those who craved the
vacated seat of power
ushered in an even greater darkness.
The story of that winter
has been completely hidden.
12.12: THE DAY
After the shocking death
of our President Park,
the whole country...
Hey.
How's that? Too serious?
No, you sound very dignified.
You could try making it more relaxed.
I look uptight?
If I'm relaxed it'll look weird.
The whole country
will be watching on TV.
The Joint Investigation Commander
will give a brief on the
president's assassination.
After the shocking death
of our President Park,
the whole nation must be sorrowful
and curious about the incident,
so we issue this interim report.
Kim asked,
"How could you run a country with
this useless maggot by your side?"
Then Dir. Kim drew a gun
and shot the Security Chief first.
Gen. Lee Tae-shin is here.
Go in.
General!
Why was Chief Jeong at
the scene of the shooting?
The Chief of Staff is not
currently under suspicion.
I heard General Chun feels
uncomfortable around you.
Is that true?
I thought that was all in the
past. But I'm not sure how he feels.
What do you think of Hanahoe?
I think private groups should
have no place in the military.
You wrote an interesting paper
when you were director of research.
It was about focusing
on military intelligence,
and getting rid of the power hungry
Defence Security Command, right?
I was a Lieutenant Colonel
then, but I was scolded so much
that I erased it from my memory.
Sir, I'd like to know
why you called me today.
I want to make you Capital
Garrison Commander.
Everyone wants that job,
so I'll give it to someone who's
not driven by greed, like you.
The army generals tell me
you're old-fashioned,
but you know your duty.
They say you don't care about politics.
That you're a real soldier. Come, sit.
You'll do it, right?
I'm truly grateful,
but may I ask the reason
for this excessive offer?
I just don't understand.
Are you turning down the
offer to be CGC Commander?
Yes, I am.
Something on your mind?
No.
General Chun is coming.
I know our vice-ministers are busy.
Sorry to call you here. Please sit.
Make yourself comfortable.
I wanted to call the
administrators too,
but as you can see, my office is tiny.
Colonel Ha. Start the meeting.
Yes, sir.
- We'll start with Foreign Affairs.
- No, no.
Home Affairs first.
Yes, sir.
Then...
- Vice Minister Yang?
- Yes.
Regarding your order...
Hearing each department's report,
Chun laughed and said, "This
is just like a Cabinet meeting!"
That's what I heard.
Just look at him.
He thinks he's the king.
What are we supposed to do about him?
As for me, I hope
our troops can be reborn
through this opportunity
to meet the expectations of the people.
That's it for now.
General!
It seems our society will take
big steps toward democracy.
What are your thoughts?
Who do you write for?
Haven't we always
been a democratic nation?
As we move past this national crisis,
I wish for our military to focus
on its core mission
of national defense.
However,
if there are people here
more concerned about politics,
I am terribly worried, and
believe it to be dangerous.
What's he saying?
Who's he talking to?
How ridiculous.
- Is he talking to us?
- Worried about us?
Better worry about himself.
Be quiet, will you?
That was a great speech.
Glad you think so.
Are you sure about making
Lee the CGC Commander?
He's not bad,
but the Garrison Command
guards the nation's capital.
The commanders today were worried...
What's your point?
It's not because he
isn't a KMA graduate,
but he can be headstrong
like other OCS graduates.
The job needs someone
more sophisticated.
Like who?
What about Gen. Roh Tae-gun?
Don't I have the authority
to appoint personnel?
Sir?
Do I need your permission
to make decisions?
Perhaps you
misunderstood, my point is...
I'll pretend I didn't
hear your point, okay?
Chief shouldn't treat you that way.
Lee doesn't know his
place to accept that job.
That's enough.
General Lee.
Congratulations.
For what?
I was so happy to hear it.
- Now that you're the CGC...
- I'm not.
You're turning it down?
You must be busy with the
DSC and the investigation.
Our service means nothing
without self-sacrifice, right?
I've been so concerned lately,
I've got no hair left.
How's the investigation on Kim going?
We'll get it done before the trial.
I heard the DSC is locking
people up indiscriminately.
Is that true?
Everyone is looking forward
to a so-called Seoul Spring.
So why arrest and torture
people not related to the case?
We all know you love our country.
Just don't be so intimidating.
I understand what you're saying.
But I'll decide how to handle that.
Yes.
I'm sure you will.
And moving around in a pack,
it doesn't look good.
General, you know,
I am honestly thinking maybe
you and I should get closer.
We could benefit from being on
the same side at this difficult time.
Everyone in the Korean
Army is on the same side.
Wow. You think so?
See you around.
How many times must I ask?
I think you should find someone better.
I'm really sorry, sir.
Stay for dinner.
It's being prepared.
I'm alright.
You can't come all this
way and leave without dinner!
Please, stay.
I think I'd better go.
If I wanted someone to do
politics, I wouldn't ask you!
After Chun took over the
DSC and the investigation
he got his hands on
all the intelligence,
and he's been acting
like the whole world is his.
Will you let Hanahoe
take over this post as well?
It's a critical time for our nation.
By myself,
I can't...
I can't do anything.
I need you to protect
Seoul. That's all I need.
As the Army Chief of
Staff, I entrust you, soldier
with this mission.
Troops, attention!
Present arms!
Allegiance!
Since its establishment, the CGC...
As commander of the CGC,
I swear to carry out my duties,
for the safety and
prosperity of the capital,
and to faithfully serve my country.
Colonel Jang Min-gi, sir!
Everyone knows Jang
is a Hanahoe member.
Yes.
Col. Won, the Military
Police Commander.
He's wily and full of tricks.
Colonel Won Gyung, sir!
Colonel Jin Young-do.
The 33rd Division Commander,
and an infamous Hanahoe member.
Colonel Jin Young-do, sir!
I'll need your help the most.
Yes, sir!
They're pledged Hanahoe members,
we can't expect them to cooperate.
So, they might disobey my orders?
Answer yes or no.
If I break this pledge
signed with blood,
I will give my life for
my fellow members.
Nothing compares to
the glory of Hanahoe!
I will forever remember the honor
of being chosen as a member.
- Allegiance!
It's run under such a cloud of secrecy,
they themselves don't
know who's in the group.
- At ease.
- I pledge my life, sir.
- Alright, alright.
Come here.
Come, sit.
Are you afraid?
It's just a chair.
No, sir. I'm not afraid.
Then sit. Think of it as your seat.
From now on, you're me.
And I'm you.
Yesterday, the US State Dept.
wired the US Embassy.
A brief message, it says
"Be wary of General Chun."
We don't need Eom or Jeon.
Hopefully all our members
will be promoted to generals.
I spoke with the Chairman.
It's a done deal.
Also, I made the reorganization
plan you asked for.
What do we do about Chief Jeong?
Make him Minister of Defense?
Take him out.
Sir, maybe you should
talk with Chief Jeong.
- To be on good terms...
- Shut it!
No point in talking
to that stubborn fool.
There was $900K in the
president's secret vault.
We gave $600K to President
Park's eldest daughter,
left $100K for us at
the Joint Investigation,
and we have $200K here for you to use.
Shouldn't that money go
to the National Treasury?
Yes, that is customary.
But then things can get messy...
So this is why people say
you have the KCIA, Presidential
Security, and the DSC
all in your pocket.
Excuse me?
Who's saying that absurd...
It's not about who.
You should think about why they say it.
You're supposed to report
these things to me before,
not afterward.
Did you expect praise?
First I need to know who's
spreading these absurd rumors.
- General.
- Yes?
You still don't know
what you did wrong?
To be frank,
I don't think I did anything wrong.
I want the Joint
Investigation to report to me
all acquired intelligence
every day, once every 3 hours.
If you wish, sir.
You're dismissed.
Get him awake, quickly.
Yes, sir.
Bring me that.
Did I sign this investigation report?
Yes, two days ago, sir.
What was the conclusion?
That Chief Jeong is under
no suspicions of conspiring.
Are you a judge?
The assassin called Jeong
to the safe house that night.
Jeong was there when
our President was shot!
Isn't it suspicious?
It sure is to me.
Find out how he and
Kim conspired together!
Why he went all the
way there just to eat!
Is Jeong a bad guy too?
I really want to know, Col. Lim.
Sir.
Yes?
We must hurry and disband
the Joint Investigation.
I said we'll do it next spring.
The trial's not even over.
This is today's morning paper.
Take a look.
Looks good to me. What's wrong?
What's wrong is that Chun
is telling them what to write.
He's beating and threatening
people with no relation to the case.
Chun, that bastard...
We can't leave him be.
But he has many supporters too.
Exactly, you know
Hanahoe is the real problem.
They're young men.
Press them too hard,
and they'll fight back.
Sir, did Chun offer you something?
Who, me?
Who's saying such nonsense?
That's outrageous.
I said no, but he
shoved it into my pocket.
I haven't even opened the envelope.
You can have it if you want.
Sir.
Alright, do as you want.
The martial law commander
has decided, so what can I do?
When we reassign command
at the end of the year,
I want to send him to
the East Coast Defense.
That far away?
- Minister, everyone's waiting.
- Okay.
Honey.
General Roh is here.
You're being sent to
the East Coast Defense.
And I'm going to the
56th Defense Division.
They're sending all of
us to useless positions.
I knew this'd happen when Lee
was named CGC commander.
We can't back out. What should we do?
All of us will end up kicked out.
Kicked out, my ass.
He's not the only one with power. I'm
Director of the Joint Investigation.
So? You're gonna lock him up?
I could.
I've got control over
all the intelligence.
I can find out what your
cousins eat for dinner.
I can even turn your dog into a commie!
Jeong, that bastard, heard His
Excellency being shot with his own ears.
But he's got nothing
to do with the plot?
Can you be sure?
Doo-gwang, he's the
martial law commander.
How can you outfox the
martial law commander?
Hey,
look at this.
Black almost lost the game.
But...
with only one move,
the tables are turned.
You wanna do as I say?
You wanna flip the tables?
Are you insane?
Well then, I'll go to the East Coast.
You go sweat your ass
off at the Defense Division
and play some tennis, you fool.
We've come far enough.
Honestly, man,
I think you should go to Chief Jeong,
kneel in front of him,
and ask for mercy.
But I know you won't do that.
Honey, aren't you having dinner?
And so the vote results were announced.
Among 2,549 total votes,
Choi Han-kyu received 2,465.
Before the election,
President Choi emphasized
stability in times of crisis...
To hell with those clowns.
No turning back.
Only forward!
Wait, hold on.
Let's think about this
a couple more days.
You idiot.
Just give up then!
You always have your way anyway!
Friend, you remember?
When our President Park
carried out the May 16 revolution,
even then, nobody knew how to react.
That's when I stepped up.
I called up all the army
cadets to do a big parade,
it was like a big party!
Stop with that talk.
That was ages ago!
You think this is the same?
Back then,
never for one second
did I doubt our President would
achieve his great revolution.
So I'm telling you...
don't dare tell me I might fail.
Cheers, everyone!
- We are...!
- One!
Sit, sit down.
Sir.
There you are.
I had a flat tire.
Oh my!
Welcome, sir!
Keep drinking. Don't stand up.
You made it!
- Welcome.
- Sir!
Come, sit.
How've you been?
You got here fast.
- Have a look.
- Sure.
We gathered today for this.
Read it over carefully.
We focused on two
suspicions of criminal facilitation.
You shut it.
You should explain this.
Ask me anything, sir.
I understand why
you want to arrest him.
But what if it fails?
Sir.
This investigation
is under military law.
So how can it fail?
This is completely illegal!
General,
then should I just crawl
away and leave the army?
It's not that, sir.
We're worried things can
get ugly while arresting Jeong.
Then it'd be a coup.
Why not call it a
grand revolution, then?
What?
If we get the President's approval,
there won't be any problem.
But won't we need to go
through the Minister of Defense?
I said, don't worry about it.
Don't worry about getting approval!
Colonels and under, listen up.
You were all smart enough to
go to the best colleges, right?
But without money or connections,
you ended up at the Military Academy.
Now with all those brainless
cronies lining up in front of you,
your chances of promotion
are shit. Is that fair?
Look me in the eye!
I'm saying, let's fix our
army, and clear out the trash!
Generals.
By spring, you all will
have to leave the army too.
Can you go to Jeong,
and ask him to promote you
instead of discharging you?
I'm sure you remember what
our President Park used to say.
"The night of revolution is
short, but its glory lasts forever."
I will maintain that glory,
but I won't keep it all to myself.
Please believe me.
Can you keep your word?
Do I need to write it in blood for you?
I'll take that, ma'am.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Thank you.
Why do I feel...
like we just might
be able to pull it off?
If we do this,
when would it be?
The day before they
announce the new Cabinet.
December 12th?
What about Gen. Lee Tae-shin
and Gen. Gong Soo-hyuk?
Lee in particular,
he's not going to listen.
This way.
Col. Moon from DSC is here to see you.
Why is he here?
General.
We'll fire two batteries
simultaneously for effect.
General Chun's birthday?
He should spend it with his family.
He's invited Gen. Gong,
Gen. Kim, and you, sir.
He wants to treat you
three to a nice warm meal.
Go tell him I'll consider
myself already treated.
Sir, I don't know if you've heard,
but there's a rumor Gen. Chun
will be sent to the east coast.
- Our general...
- And what did he say?
Well, he's not very pleased.
But he's a man with a big
heart, so he just laughed it off.
General, we're ready.
Anyway, before he leaves,
he wants to spend time
with the three of you...
Troops!
Ready guns!
- Fire!
You sure he's coming?
I'm almost sure.
What? "Almost"?
Never seen you so doubtful, Moon.
I'll make him come, sir.
Right. He's a stubborn mule,
so you have to keep at him.
I still think we should grab Jeong
on his way to the residence...
No, let me explain it again.
Look, we'll all gather
at the 30th Security.
Even if shots are
fired during the arrest,
DECEMBER 12
most of CGC's combat troops are here.
There are only two security
groups in this whole area.
So, if we set up our base
in the 30th Security,
no one can touch us.
From 9 a.m.,
it's possible to monitor all
communication networks.
Good afternoon, sir.
You're early.
Where is Gen. Chun?
Gentlemen.
Why wait out here?
At least you recognized me.
I thought you forgot your wife's face.
Come on.
I plan to go home
today, even if it's late.
Nice to hear you say it at least.
You're not skipping meals, are you?
They won't let a general starve.
Come inside.
I'm sure you're busy.
You go in.
Come on, have a cup of warm tea.
I brought new underwear and
socks, so change if you need to.
Don't embarrass me.
Hello, ma'am.
- Colonel, it's been awhile.
- Yes.
Sir, we're ready to start the meeting.
- To make it to that dinner...
- Right, the one with Chun?
I'll get going now.
General!
General Lee will attend tonight.
Great.
Get the lights.
I'll describe today's plan.
Gen. Chun will get the President's
approval at around 18:30.
At the same time,
Jeong will be arrested.
Colonels Ha and Yoon
will oversee the arrest.
They have troops standing by now.
Just in case,
we'll keep these three
men occupied at the party,
so it'll be hard for them
to mobilize their troops.
Most important
is to get the President's
approval at the time of arrest.
If we carry this out legally,
our plan will succeed.
Wipe those frowns off your faces!
I'll wrap this up for sure.
Col. Lim!
What's wrong?
Jeong wants to see you at Army HQ.
Did he find out?
No way.
It seemed like he had no idea.
Stay calm and go see him.
General Chun is here.
Sir, you asked to see me?
I know what you're thinking, General.
Of course I do.
You must've been upset,
hearing about your new post.
But what does it matter
where a soldier serves?
I hope you'll do this for us
to help reform the troops.
Of course, sir.
Don't you worry.
Anyway, I have a favor to ask.
Things have been chaotic lately,
and we've gotten less
vigilant about the North.
Soon, everyone will be
focused on Director Kim's trial.
I thought you might make Kim
mention the threat of pro-communists
during his final statement.
That is a great idea.
Anyway, please wrap things up well.
Sir.
I must report something to
you about the investigation.
Can I have my men visit
you at the residence tonight?
Can't we do it tomorrow?
It won't take long.
These damn judges are so impatient.
Why did he want to see you?
Give me a cigarette.
Looks like I picked
the perfect party day.
Report to General Roh.
We're sticking to the plan!
Where are we?
Does Chun drink at
these kinds of places?
Welcome, sir.
- Won Gyung?
- Yes, sir.
Why are you here?
Gen. Chun was called by the
Chief and is running a bit late.
He asked me to keep you company.
The host isn't here?
- Let's just go.
- Pardon, sir?
You heard me.
- Back to Garrison Command.
- Yes, sir.
Wait, General!
Hey, General.
What's your business?
It's General Chun.
It's the DSC Director of Intelligence.
Identity confirmed!
- Hello, General.
- It's been a while.
You've come a long way. Please.
We're relieving the guards.
It's the new shift of
guards. Just let them in.
But...
There are much more than usual.
What the hell do you mean?
We need to check inside the vehicles.
Everyone step out, please.
Hey, no need for that.
Yes, I know. But we have rules.
You little...
All four of you will be seeing him?
This way, please.
Would you like to see
our girls perform, sir?
Is Chun coming or not?
Well...
I'll go call the Chief's residence
to see when he's coming.
Don't bother.
Madame, where's the phone here?
Sir, I'll make the call.
You stay out of it.
Sir, I'll check with
the Chief's residence.
- Why don't you just sit?
- He'll be here soon.
- Won, go make the call.
- Yes, sir.
Mr. President.
Sir, sorry to bother
you at this late hour.
What brings you here?
Something requires
your approval right now.
My approval, at this hour?
Yes, I'm terribly sorry.
It is an urgent matter.
Please, sit.
I'm leaving with my wife
soon, so make it quick.
It's been a while.
Have a seat.
You're the DSC Head of Intelligence?
Yes, sir.
Gen. Chun said it's urgent. What is it?
We need your statement
for Director Kim's trial.
My statement?
What more do you need?
It'll just be a simple question.
Really?
Well, whatever it is,
let's take care of it here.
That's not possible.
We'd like you to come
to where we can record it.
Record it?
Yes, sir.
You think I don't know what that means?
Director Kim has a new statement.
What kind of statement?
A statement saying you received money.
That's absurd!
I was confirmed to have no part in it!
It's an order from our superiors.
Your superiors? Listen here.
I give orders to your superior!
Who the hell was it?
Unless it was the President.
The President told you to do this?
Yes, sir.
It can't be.
We talked just yesterday.
Adjutant! Come here!
Yes, sir.
Call the President
immediately. Tell him it's urgent.
- Yes, sir.
- What's this? What are you guys?
Stop that call, now!
Answer me!
- What was that?
- Sir, come with us.
Don't move!
Chief!
- Drop your gun!
- Marines!
Do something!
Looks like Chun won't be joining us.
He summons all three capital
defense commanders to one place,
and makes us wait.
Hey, Won.
Yes, sir.
What happened to Chun?
He said he left the residence.
There seems to be a lot of traffic.
Sir, let's leave in 10 minutes.
Freeze!
Out of the way!
Stop firing, you bastards!
- Colonel...
- Unload everyone.
Shots have been fired
at the Chief's residence.
Shit, who shot first?
And the Chief? Did they arrest him?
Did they leave the compound or not?
- What about General Chun?
- We need approval.
You should've informed Chun first!
He better have the
President's approval!
Please, let me figure this out first.
Wasn't he...
cleared of all charges?
We must cross-examine him with
Kim to make sure he's really innocent.
Marines! Marines!
I'm the chief of staff!
Cover him up!
They're kidnapping me!
Marines...
What's going on?
It's a special operation. Back off.
You two! Hold it right there!
Marines!
Chief!
- Honey.
- What?
You scared me.
Are we at war?
What do we do?
Sir!
There was a shooting
at the Chief's residence.
I know. His wife called...
Taxi!
Good evening.
Where to?
Where's Colonel Won?
He was using the toilet. I'm not sure.
Did they arrest...
Won!
Won Gyung.
What are you doing?
Come on out.
Now!
Won.
Stop right there!
Sir!
We have a situation
at the Chief's residence.
What is it?
What?
As long as you authorize
it, there's no problem, sir.
Chief Jeong is your direct superior,
and he's the martial law commander
appointed by the state council.
Come back tomorrow with the Minister.
Tomorrow is too late.
Approve this now, please.
I said to wait outside. Stay put.
Yes.
Hold on.
So, you're saying
the President is fine?
Yes, that's right.
But...
Is something wrong?
Attention everyone!
The commander's here.
Is everyone on the way?
The 30th and 33rd
Security are not responding.
Where's the MP deputy?
Lt. Col. Heo is on his way.
- Is that him?
- Yes, sir.
Give it to me.
Lt. Colonel, it's me.
Take the APCs and strike force,
and go to the Chief's residence.
Sir...
Call the medical unit!
Take him to the
hospital! Why is he here?
Kwon, are you alright?
We were hit by the Security Command.
The DSC?
What about the Chief?
I just arrived at the army bunker.
I'll look into Chun's whereabouts.
Okay. I'm heading to
the Chief's residence.
You search the DSC and
Prime Minister's residence,
and find that bastard Chun!
Then, we ask that
bastard his motive for...
Why are you still standing around?
There's nothing I can do!
- I got it.
- Yes, sir.
This is Lt. Col. Lee at the guardhouse.
This is the Provost Marshal.
What's the status there?
The DSC commander
is visiting, but that's it.
Chun is there now?
Yes, he came to see the
President about an hour ago.
Is something wrong, sir?
I've got one question.
Give me a straight answer.
Yes, sir.
Are you with Hanahoe?
Sir?
No. Not at all, sir.
Okay.
Listen to me carefully.
When General Chun
comes out, arrest him at once.
Pardon?
Get General Roh, now!
Chun abducted our Chief of Staff.
You have to be discreet.
There's no room for mistakes.
You may open fire if he resists.
Arrest him at all costs.
- Presidential Security.
- Chief Kang.
It's me, Roh.
Yes, General.
See one of our men there?
- You know, Lt. Col. Lim.
- Ah, yes.
Hello, sir.
Get General Chun out of there.
He's still with the president.
Go get him now!
Lt. Colonel, come here.
Tell me what's happening, now!
Call me when you get
through to the Minister.
Mr. President, it's urgent.
This cannot wait any longer.
Didn't I tell you already?
By protocol, you must
consult the Minister first.
Protocol...
Sure, that's important.
And that's why I'm begging
for your decision on this matter.
Look, Commander.
I intend to follow the rules.
Excuse me, Mr. President.
The Security Command
is asking for the General.
Who is?
Sir, please stay low.
Is the Chief in there?
What's his location?
It seems like he's
not in there anymore.
What?
Hold your fire! Stop!
Why are they shooting at us?
33rd MPs and Marine Guards
are exchanging fire inside,
and the MPs say they came as backup...
The Marines claim
that the MPs took the
Chief away by force.
Since when did they
have so many guards?
Halt!
They're here to get me, these bastards.
Turn off the engine, please.
I said, turn it off.
Turn it off.
We have the Commander's car.
Good.
Disarm and arrest them immediately.
General, come.
General Kim.
Listen, we have to arrest
the Security Commander.
Go.
Go now.
- The gate's closed.
- Hurry, damn it!
All personnel, step out of the car.
Captain, do you know who's in the back?
Yes, step out please.
Driver first.
Out of the car, now!
Move away from the car.
Come forward.
Step out.
Step out, now.
Yes, sir.
This is the Vice Chief of
Staff. What's the situation?
We have the Commander's vehicle,
and we're about to arrest him, sir.
What, arrest him?
Wait.
Look, don't arrest him.
Just tell him to wait there.
But it's the Provost Marshal's order.
Who do you think I was just briefed by?
Do as I say.
We must arrest him right now.
Wait, Captain!
Hold up!
The General stays
inside? Are we standing by?
Commander!
It's the Vice Chief of Staff.
- Yes?
- General.
You ordered the arrest
without my permission?
Sir, to find out where the Chief is...
Don't you know we need the consent
of the martial law commander first?
How can we do that
when he's the one taken?
That doesn't give you an excuse.
Chun called me, the Provost Marshal,
the Special Warfare Commander tonight,
and raided the Chief's
residence at the same time.
To rescue the Chief,
we must arrest Chun and...
Listen to me, General.
Don't jump to conclusions.
We could all get in trouble.
Just don't stir things up.
- Sir, I didn't start this.
- Yeah, okay.
Sir, please. We can't let this happen!
This is all a plot by Chun and Hanahoe.
Gosh...
I'm the one to judge here.
I'll take care of it, okay?
Get him to open the gate.
You two open the gate.
Sir?
Open the gate.
Move away from the vehicle.
Move now!
Captain!
Captain! Come here.
Yes, sir. Eyes on them.
I need you to open the gate.
Lt. Colonel? Stop!
Get out of the car!
Your gun...
Lt. Colonel! Turn off the car! Get out!
- Should we?
- Go now, you idiot!
Floor it!
Sir, are you all right?
Me?
I'm fine.
Take me to 30th Security.
He got away?
I'm sorry, General.
How could you lose him?
Hey, it's me.
You're in no position to say that.
Isn't 30th Security under your command?
Yes, it is.
Chun Doo-gwang, Roh Tae-gun,
and the whole gang were
gathered there since this afternoon.
How could you not know
that as its commander?
Do your job first
before you lecture us.
We can't wait any longer.
Declare DEFCON 1.
- Lt. Colonel.
- Yes?
Follow my orders exactly!
Those 33rd MPs inside,
they came to abduct the
Chief and got stuck there.
Put two APCs close together,
and push your way in with Marines.
- Understand?
- Yes, sir.
Have all COs report to...
This is the Commander.
Issue arrest orders for Jang
Min-gi, Won Gyung and Jin Young-do.
You have permission
to fire if they resist.
Yes, open fire!
Shoot them!
The criminals who abducted
the Martial Law Commander
- are gathered in the 30th Security
- They can hear too?
What's going on?
and ignoring their superiors' command.
Our military condemn this action
as a coup d'tat led by the DSC,
and name the B2 Bunker
as command center,
as we're now in a state of war.
Today at 20:20, I declare
DEFCON 1 to all forces.
- Captain, move your men out!
- Yes, sir!
Move!
They want us to send back the Chief?
It was a lost cause from the start.
Shit!
I told you this would happen.
Yeah...
We need to keep calm, especially now.
Where's Chun? Did he get the approval?
I don't have the damn approval yet.
Sir.
Don't worry.
We just need to find
the Minister of Defense.
Chun, did you not hear what happened?
How could you let it come to this?
Come to what?
You heard we successfully
arrested Chief Jeong.
Doo-gwang!
Yes, what?
They declared DEFCON 1.
Now we're guilty of treason.
All of us are finished!
Seriously, gentleman.
Did you not expect this?
Fail and it's treason,
succeed and it's revolution!
We're only...
What time is it?
It's been only 98 minutes.
You want to surrender without a fight?
You, go find the Minister.
Get our men to drag his ass over here.
Look here, Minister.
Why come here instead of your office?
We can't do anything
for you at this moment.
The North can take this chance
to attack us, don't you think?
We're using all our resources
to locate the Minister,
so we'll find him soon.
Where the hell did he run off to?
He's supposed to be
Minister of Defense...
- Where is he?
- Hiding somewhere.
Jang speaking.
What are you doing there?
Didn't you get my order?
Can someone...
answer this please?
- Who is it?
- The CGC Commander.
Answer me.
Sir...
Answer me!
You do it.
Lee, this is Han.
What are you doing there?
That's my unit there.
I know.
Why don't you come over here,
and listen to General Chun?
Is he there?
Put him on the phone.
I have something to say to him.
He wants you.
Chun, I know you can hear me.
Bring the Chief back
to the Army HQ now.
And all of you idiots,
you know 30th Security
is under my command.
So return to your unit.
Especially my men, Jang, Won and Jin,
report to me right now.
Lee, please calm down.
Who is this?
This is Lt. Gen. Bae, okay?
We too are concerned
about this country...
You brainless piece of shit.
- Is that why you staged a coup?
- Watch it, Lee.
All of you stay right there.
I'll bring tanks myself and
crush your fucking skulls.
Shit.
How typical of his background.
He's got a dirty mouth.
How can you laugh?
His troops are only an hour from here.
If we don't resolve this,
it'll be our graveyard.
Graveyard, my ass.
Keep your mouth shut.
What?
Hee-chul.
Yes, sir.
I need the 2nd Airborne.
- Pardon?
- Hold on.
Once we involve Airbornes,
there's no turning back.
We'll go to war then.
That's different from
arresting the Chief.
The war already began
when we made that arrest.
Lee's coming here with tanks.
He doesn't make empty threats.
You want to die here?
Or take over Seoul first?
Commander Roh!
My troops must hold the front line.
Tonight, this is the front line.
If Lee gets the upper
hand, we're finished.
Listen,
what if the North invades while
the border is left unguarded?
Kim Il-sung has no plan to
invade tonight. Trust me.
Why trust you?
We got into this mess...
Brother!
Tell me, Commander Roh!
Move!
Their defense will be hard to break.
But we have the authority to command
the 26th and 30th Divisions
in the North and the West.
The problem is the Airbornes
that joined the rebels.
The 2nd, 6th and 4th Airbornes
are led by Hanahoe key figures.
Not only are they close to Seoul,
they're fast and highly capable.
The 8th Airborne Brigadier
isn't one of them.
He's an OCS graduate like me.
First, mobilize the 8th Airborne.
We'll also bring the 30th
and 26th Divisions into Seoul,
while asking the Third Corps
for the Mechanized Infantry.
Then, the enemy will be cut off.
And the Tank Corps? Any news yet?
I spoke to its commander,
but he's Hanahoe.
He won't budge.
- Gimpo Field Artillery.
- Yes.
Any Hanahoe members there?
There's none. You
have their loyalty, sir.
Good.
Tell me, who's with Hanahoe here?
What a bunch of
feeble-minded cowards...
You too!
You wimp.
Don't give me that.
I trusted you with my life!
How could you say that to me?
Exactly...
My point exactly, you idiot.
That's why I'm asking for your help.
General Roh.
Let's go back in.
I'm not a coward.
You know that, right?
Come on.
I made my decision.
The train's running at full
steam. Who wants to jump out?
My 9th Division...
- will send in two regiments.
- What?
If you want out, now's the time.
When this door closes,
you're with me to the end.
General Chun.
What can we do for you?
Let's leave Roh in charge here,
and go back to the
President for the approval.
- Destination Capitol Hall. Move.
- Sir.
Is it right to pull back
our men from the front?
If there's a war tonight,
it'll be here, understand?
I don't understand, sir.
How can we pull back
the frontline unit?
General Kim...
How many times do I have to tell you?
The North won't invade!
Just... trust me on this.
We're lucky the
capital's top commanders
are all on our side.
We're surely at an advantage.
How dare they...
That's right.
General,
we can try talking to
them and stall for time.
Then they'll be exhausted
and give up the fight...
Sir, what are you talking
about? We need to react quickly!
You scared me.
General, you don't have to
yell at me in front of everyone.
Sir, are you sure about this?
Want me to do it for you?
Yeah, it's me.
Get everyone armed. We're moving out.
Get your shit together
and open your ears!
The destination is...
Army HQ in Samgakji.
The 2nd and 4th Airborne
aren't responding?
Sir, CGC Commander's on the line.
They're all in it
together. Don't trust them.
They're all moving in unison now.
So, I need you to send 8th Airborne
to the 30th Security immediately.
8th Airborne is now returning
to its base after training
Call them in right now!
This is a greatly urgent matter.
Okay, okay.
I'll do as you say.
Major Oh, still no response
from 2nd and 4th Airborne?
General.
The 2nd Airborne is coming to Seoul.
What?
Sir, this is Major Oh.
Please respond.
The Commander's ordered
you to return immediately.
One says to move out,
the other, to return...
- What the hell is going on?
- Sir.
- Should I turn it off?
- Sir!
It's on its way here?
15 km away, sir.
2nd Airborne?
What was the Special
Warfare Commander doing?
Hanahoe must have given the order.
The situation in CGC is no different.
- That's outrageous!
- They'll be here any minute.
We have no defense
force here. What do we do?
Sir, we need a strong offensive action.
Like what?
Muster all available forces
and send them out now!
How dare they do this
under an elected president?
What did the Minister say?
We can't reach him.
Abducting the army chief of staff
is clearly an act of insurrection.
You're right.
I can't agree more. They're imbeciles!
To stop the 2nd Airborne,
we need the Mechanized
Infantry and 26th Division.
All right. I'll give
them the orders now.
I'm counting on you.
Sure, don't worry.
The Mechanized Infantry
won't make it in time
to stop the 2nd Airborne
crossing the river.
Sir, they are incredibly fast.
Hold on, let me think.
Those bastards...
For them to enter Seoul...
They must come through here.
Over the 2nd Hangang Bridge,
maybe the Seoul Bridge,
or they'll go the long way around
and cross the 1st Hangang Bridge.
But it'd require a division to
block all Han River bridges.
No.
We're not blocking them.
The citizens will.
Close all bridges in
my area of command.
Both directions entirely.
Stop the car.
All vehicles, halt!
Just push through them.
Or go against the traffic!
- Take the opposite lane.
- Give me a smoke.
Who follows traffic
laws in a war situation?
The opposite lanes are
jammed with civilian cars too.
They can take 1st Hangang
Bridge or Seoul Bridge.
From here to 3rd Hangang
Bridge, all bridges are blocked.
Haengju Bridge.
CGC doesn't control this one.
That's right.
General, Haengju Bridge is
under your command, isn't it?
I need you to block the
bridge to hinder their advance.
I understand.
We'll bolster security
and cut off the passage.
If needed, I can back you
up with our artillery brigade.
No, it's fine.
We have two companies
arriving shortly, fully armed.
Give us some time.
Thank you.
Everyone heard that?
If this bridge is
blocked, we're screwed.
If the Airborne doesn't
cross, you'll be jailed for life.
Use all your connections
in the 30th Division
and find a way for me
to talk to its commander.
Tonight, it all comes down to
whose troops enter Seoul first.
They'll block all lanes
and set up machine guns.
Okay, good.
Yes.
Commander, this is
the DSC Chief Secretary.
I'm calling about the conversation
you just had with General Lee.
Who the hell are you?
How'd you hear our conversation?
Let's just say we have
ears all over the network.
You'll be sorry you said that.
- What's your name and rank?
- The odds are against you.
9th Division's on its
way. 4th Airborne, too.
Even if you block the bridge,
it's only a matter of time.
You fucking idiot!
You pulled back the frontline unit?
- Have you lost it?
- Many generals have already...
joined this great cause.
Damn you...
I'll keep listening for the
wise decision you'll take.
Quickly!
- You bastard!
- Son of a bitch!
- Disarm them!
- Bastards!
Attention!
Salute the President!
Allegiance!
Order arms!
You seem busy tonight, General.
I'm sorry, Mr. President.
The reason why we're here is...
What did you do to the Chief
that soldiers are being shot?
There was a small
disturbance, but as you can see,
the whole army is supporting the arrest
and the investigation of Chief Jeong.
So...
Do you have the Minister's consent?
How could you arrest
the martial law commander
without due process?
Lt. Gen. Han Young-gu,
if I may, Mr. President.
If you delay the approval,
the situation could escalate
into civil war in no time.
Civil war?
Hey, Captain.
I'm from CGC. Where's the control line?
We were ordered to stand down.
It's your commander's
order. Set up barricades now.
We were ordered by the commander too.
- You sure it was him?
- Yes, sir.
There was a mix-up in communication,
but I can explain it to the Army HQ.
We need your approval first, though.
Enough!
Mr. President already told you
to get the Minister's consent first!
Prime Minister, he's gone
missing. What do you want us to do?
So, you threaten the
President with talk of civil war?
We never threatened him!
How can they be so obtuse...
General, what's that attitude?
We're not bullies, are we?
Mr. President, forgive
our rude behavior.
I've made myself clear.
You're dismissed.
Shit.
We'll wait until you approve this.
Why did you tell them to stand down?
I was just informed by
Janggok Checkpoint
that the 9th Division is coming.
What?
This is more serious than I thought.
Plus, we can't have all-out
war with 2nd Airborne...
That's why we need to stop them.
If we don't do anything, they'll
march straight to Army HQ.
What can we do when
they're listening to our calls?
I'm sorry.
General Roh called
in his frontline troops.
How can they leave us
exposed to the North?
They must fear Chun
more than Kim Il-sung.
I'm more worried about
DSC listening in on our calls.
Attention, all soldiers.
The following men may be shot on sight.
Turn it up.
Gen. Chun, Gen. Roh, Bae, Han and Do,
and convicted CGC officers
Col. Jang, Jin and Won,
DSC officers Moon, Ha and Lim
and anyone giving them aid...
Where's the 2nd Airborne?
Sir, I did what I could.
You little shit, answer me.
Did they cross the bridge or not?
Colonel!
Bring the barricades! Hurry!
You two bring those, now!
An update from Haengju Bridge.
2nd Airborne is at the bridge.
They'll be crossing any minute.
Good.
Shouldn't take long, right?
Colonel.
This is the Vice Chief of Staff.
Return to base immediately.
The moment you cross the bridge,
we have no choice but to engage.
If it results in casualties,
I'll court-martial all of
you to maximum penalties!
They're not going to stop.
They're on the bridge!
Wait!
Hey, what's that?
What is he doing there?
Please turn back.
Sir, he's a two-star.
- Run him over.
- Sir?
Just hit the gas!
What if they really court-martial us?
Let's check first.
This is your Commander.
2nd Airborne, turn around.
Return to base, and
no one will be punished.
If you enter Seoul,
it's all-out war, understand?
Return to your base now.
Who's blocking them? 30th Division?
I'm not sure.
It's... it's one man.
One?
- Just one?
- What the hell? Give it to me.
- What's going on?
- Give me the fucking phone!
There's a man standing
in the middle of the bridge.
Yes, General.
They've stopped in the middle.
Huh? They're turning back.
They are going back
south of the bridge!
Are they taking fire?
- No, they're not.
- Then why?
Why?
How dare he disobey my order!
You're absolutely sure
they're going back?
I'm watching it now.
2nd Airborne has turned back.
We still must keep our guard up!
Get me something to drink.
That old fart.
2nd Airborne's turning
back from Haengju Bridge.
Goddammit! Who ordered it?
Lee was blocking the bridge,
and the Army HQ got to them.
Those sons of bitches...
Is Do Hee-chul still
at the 30th Security?
Yes, sir.
Hee-chul.
My brother, Hee-chul.
What's going on, sir?
You go there yourself, okay?
Go bring the 2nd Airborne. All of them.
You're kidding.
Did you laugh?
What the hell?
- You think I'm kidding?
- Sir, stop.
Sir!
What are you doing?
I'm not shooting. Let me go!
Hee-chul, come here. Come right here!
Grab the gun.
Grab it!
If you don't want to go,
shoot right through my heart.
Shoot me!
I want you to start making
calls using all your connections!
Stop them from making any move.
If we fail, we'll lose this war.
Take it.
Let me ask one thing.
Are you sure Chief Jeong is safe?
Floor it! He told me to
bring our men at once!
General Chun asked me! Of all people!
Kang, turn the car around.
I need to go to Third Corps myself.
- What are you doing here?
- Pardon?
Go back out there.
I just got the radio. The
Commander ordered us here.
- Did you laugh?
- Sorry?
Did you just laugh at me?
No, sir. I didn't laugh.
- You just did, you bastard.
- What's wrong?
Grab it. Grab it!
Please calm down!
Jeez, you shit.
- Just grab it.
- Sir, please!
If you want to disobey
me, just shoot me right here.
Hee-chul did it!
2nd Airborne is moving out again.
You think people like to give orders?
What?
You know, all human beings
want someone strong to lead them.
Everyone is waiting.
Those guys in there,
they're hoping to eat
some crumbs off the table.
I'll shove plenty down their throats!
You don't need to come here.
Our commanding officers
don't wish to intervene.
Commander,
at least send your battalion
units to the Army HQ please.
General, haven't you heard?
I was just informed too.
2nd Airborne is coming back.
What?
I'll try to convince my men.
But don't get your hopes up. Goodbye.
Commander!
Brigadier General!
A call for you, sir.
- Is it the DSC again?
- The CGC Commander, sir.
- Park, speaking.
- This is Lee Tae-shin.
- Brigadier, I know you have a lot...
- Sir, get to the point.
Mobilize 8th Airborne to Seoul, please.
These are Airbornes
you're talking about.
If we engage 2nd Airborne,
that'll be all-out war.
That's exactly why I need
you to come before they do.
Why the 8th Airborne?
Why do we have to take the lead?
2nd, 4th, 6th Airbornes
are in Hanahoe's control.
We are greatly outnumbered.
Brigadier.
Only the 8th Airborne
can enter Seoul in time.
- That's why I'm asking...
- Please stop.
8th Airborne will stay out of it.
If you come first to
establish a defense line
and strike the 30th
Security with my men,
we can stop them.
Brigadier?
Brigadier!
Go on.
I don't want to have this fight either.
But we can't let them have Seoul.
Think about why you and
I still wear this uniform...
Are we not soldiers who
must fight when needed?
I will hold my ground.
Win or lose,
I'll fight anyway.
We'll mobilize.
I'll be at the Army HQ in an hour.
Thank you.
Goddammit!
8th Airborne is coming. Even
sooner than 2nd Airborne.
What?
Shit!
Do you know any officers there?
We have no connection there.
I knew this would happen.
Do you know anyone?
This had to be executed perfectly!
We should've stuck
to the plan. We're dead!
General Chun, say something!
Look at them.
How did these cowering
bastards earn their stars?
His Excellency must've
feared another coup,
he only pinned stars on idiots.
Chun! What did you just say?
Huh?
No, no.
Not the generals here.
I meant the shit stars at the Army HQ.
You crazy fool. What
took you so long to call me?
I'm sorry, General.
I'll get an earful later.
No, I mean
Why on earth did you stage this mutiny?
Chief Jeong is perfectly safe.
I was going to ask him a few
questions and send him back.
You guys are overreacting.
I really don't understand.
Is that supposed to be a joke?
Abducting the martial law commander
without the President's approval
is a clear coup d'tat!
Gosh.
I'll get you that damn
approval. That's no big deal.
And General, no one's staging a coup.
The Korean Army is
all on the same side.
That's a very serious allegation
you're making right now.
Why did you call?
You going to surrender?
General Min.
I'm listening.
General Chun.
General Chun?
I'll tell the 2nd Airborne to return.
In return,
order your men to do the same.
- Both sides take a step back?
- Yes.
I'm proposing a gentlemen's agreement.
No.
Sir,
you can't accept that.
They won't back off so easily.
General, don't trust them.
General, please!
General Chun, withdraw
2nd Airborne first.
Then I'll have 8th Airborne return.
Yes, sir. Stop the car.
What? They're going back again.
We're almost there.
Can't we just stand by here?
No, we confirmed their withdrawal.
You're putting our agreement at risk.
There are rebels left
at the 30th Security,
so we must stop them.
We made an agreement,
so there are no rebels!
I'm ordering you to
return to your base.
You're withdrawing the 8th Airborne?
What nonsense is that?
I've put you through, so
you can speak up now.
This is Special Warfare
Commander Gong Soo-hyuk.
Everyone, please listen to me.
A gentlemen's agreement?
What kind of bullshit is that?
Do Hee-chul at 2nd Airborne
disobeyed his superior
and raced like a mad dog
to take down all of you standing there.
You can't make a pact
with a son of a bitch like...
We're ready to cross, sir.
Let's go.
Brigadier, don't leave.
You've got to come back.
The order is from the Army HQ.
Even my Commander
is under their orders.
How can I refuse?
Then stop for a second,
and stand by where you are.
I really want to,
but the Vice Chief
of Staff told us not to.
Trust me.
The rebels are lying.
You must know that too.
I'm sorry, Commander.
Sorry.
8th Airborne is gone.
Hey, put it down.
You won't shoot me.
Allegiance!
Are they looking for me?
Gentlemen.
Good work.
You are all here.
Minister! Where have you been?
I was at the Combined Forces Command.
I heard about the incident,
so I talked to the US
ambassador and CFC commander,
and made some
analysis of the situation.
Minister!
I'm glad you're here.
Please order Chun's arrest right now.
Stay out of this.
Where do I sit?
This way, Minister.
I talked Chun out of
involving our Airbornes.
So if you could explain to them...
Seriously, you should've
talked to them in the first place!
How thoughtless of you
to declare DEFCON 1.
Sir, what do you mean?
The Army Chief of Staff is
abducted. This is a coup d'tat.
Who are you? Oh, the Provost Marshal.
His gang are scum who
tried to take over the country!
Hey!
Stop stuttering!
Did you see it?
What is it?
2nd Airborne crossed the
bridge and are coming this way.
What?
Defending the capital
is everyone's mission!
Don't hang up!
You've got to listen to me.
This is a coup d'tat!
We must defend Seoul!
I told you already!
Hurry up!
General.
- He's looking for you inside.
- Who is?
The Minister, sir.
Can't we ask the US
Army for combat troops?
We have less than 30 minutes...
What's the use of staying here?
We need to go where
we can be protected.
- How about the CGC?
- What?
- At least General Lee is there.
- Right.
Did you ask for me?
Do you know my car?
Is my Ford still out there?
Minister, then who
will defend this place?
That's not the minister's job, is it?
Commander!
The Army HQ command
is coming over to us.
They all want to hide behind your back.
If Chun really wins
control of the army,
won't they make you into a scapegoat?
Kang Dong-chan!
Watch your mouth.
Yes, sir. I'm sorry.
Commander!
Sir, are you really
giving up this place?
I heard CGC is running
short on soldiers, too.
But we have nowhere to go.
We can't just hand it over to them!
Once we move the command,
I'll sort things out with Chun.
It'll just take 5 minutes to talk.
- Chun always listens to me...
- How can you say that as minister?
Who do you think you are?
How dare a one-star
talk back to the minister?
You arrogant little shit.
I said I'll talk to Chun
and work things out!
Who has a better idea? Anyone?
Why should we humor
someone who started a coup?
Come to your senses, please!
- General.
- Joon-yup...
I'll do it! I'll stop them somehow.
Please don't abandon your posts.
If we let them take this country,
it'll be a great dishonor to this army.
Generals, I beg you with all my heart.
CGC is right around the
corner, so hop in any car.
Where's my car?
This is ours. Yours is up front!
Oh, okay.
- Those skanks!
- Take the one behind!
The Minister.
Where'd he go now?
- Where did our Minister go?
- He left already.
They abandoned the HQ and fled to CGC.
Those idiots.
That bunker is impenetrable.
Saved us from trouble.
It's not over yet. We haven't
captured Lee and Gong.
Jang, any news from Kim Chang-se?
He's ready to take the
Special Warfare Command.
Major Oh at the commander's
office is your friend?
He's a year below me, sir.
We're also neighbors. Our
wives know each other well.
It's nothing personal,
so just follow orders as a soldier.
Are you staying? We gotta get out.
But our Commander
didn't give the order yet...
If you wish to leave,
you are free to go.
Commander, you must evacuate now.
Don't worry about me.
Everyone, go.
That's an order.
Leave!
Sorry, sir.
Commander.
- Sir, you should first...
- Major Oh.
I want you to leave with others.
Go.
Attack!
What are you doing?
I ordered you to evacuate.
If you're here, I should be too, sir.
Hey, I can protect myself!
I know, sir.
But you'll be lonely here.
Jin-ho.
Aren't you scared?
To be honest,
I am, sir.
But it's okay because
I'm with you, sir.
Oh Jin-ho.
I thought you were smart,
but I guess you're a bit slow.
Hey, stop.
Step back.
We've seized the whole building!
Do not resist and step out!
Open the door on the count of five,
or we'll shoot.
Sir, let's just fire.
Major Oh, it's me.
Hey, Jin-ho.
Answer me.
I'm warning you.
Whoever you are,
step one foot in this office,
and I'll fire!
Jin-ho.
Take cover.
This is the Brigadier.
What's taking so long? Take them out!
He's no longer your commander!
Finish them off!
Jin-ho, are you okay?
I'm fine, sir!
Get back!
Sergeant!
Sir!
Are you alright?
Bastards!
Stop!
Cease fire!
Jin-ho.
Hey.
Son of a bitch...
Commander, you're under arrest.
Call the medic.
We gotta save Jin-ho.
Take your hands off him!
He's your friend.
Your closest friend!
Get the medic.
Kim Chang-se.
I led you for 15 years...
thought of you as my son.
How do you like being Chun's dog?
It's nothing personal, Commander.
If the medic's not coming,
take him yourselves!
- Take him now.
- Yes, sir.
Jin-ho.
Let me go.
Let go, you bastards!
No!
Jin-ho... Jin-ho!
Jin-ho!
Commander, it's Lee.
He's just been arrested.
Who are you?
The tables have completely turned.
Please make a wise decision
to avoid unnecessary sacrifice.
They are here.
Commander.
Must be tough.
Man, it's cold.
Take out the soldiers
on the first floor!
The gate is open, lead
car entering now.
Great work!
What?
Hands in the air!
- It's me.
- Shut up and come out!
I'm the Minister.
- I hear you. Come out!
- I said I'm the Minister!
I'm Noh Guk-sang,
the Minister of Defense!
Push your way in!
Hurry!
Don't move! Drop your guns!
Now!
You can't enter here.
Move!
- Let go!
- No.
- You bastard!
- I said no!
- You fuck...
- I said no! No!
General, what's the status there?
Commander, I'm so sorry.
You, get up!
Looks like I'm done.
What's going on?
General Kim, are you okay?
You're our last hope.
Colonel Kang.
Yes, sir.
Assemble all available
soldiers in the drill ground now.
General!
What are you going to do?
I'm going to take down Chun.
Damn.
- Hello?
- Did I wake you?
Not at all.
I thought you'd come
home, will it be later?
I hate to say this.
But I don't think I can come today.
I was going to make your
favorite stew for breakfast.
Can't you come in the morning?
I'm really sorry.
What's with you saying sorry today?
Don't skip meals even if you're busy.
I'll just quit if they starve me.
Stop joking about that. It's not funny.
Honey,
is something wrong?
No.
Oh, honey.
Huh?
I almost forgot to tell you.
There's a scarf inside your bag.
I bought it for you at the market.
It's cold outside.
Wear it when you go out.
- Goodbye, then.
- Okay.
- Ready in 5 minutes.
- How many do we have?
Four tanks, four APCs,
and about 100 soldiers including
heavy weapon squads, sir.
I told you to include
all non-combat soldiers.
They're all included.
Commander.
- Permission to speak freely, sir?
- Keep it short.
I think you've done enough.
Enough?
It's over already.
We lost the Ministry of
Defense and the bunker.
Those generals in the situation room
also say it's useless to fight.
Even when the rebels
are taking over the country?
Did you get a call from them, too?
Didn't you know?
Not just me, everyone here got a call!
Of course, I swore at them and hung up.
Good job.
Commander.
Everyone gave in except for you.
Even if we continue to fight,
there's no chance we'll win.
So?
When spring comes,
shouldn't you see
your son start college?
How dare you!
Do you really want to see your
commander surrender to Chun?
My country's falling to
traitors right before my eyes...
And no soldier will fight to the end.
What kind of army is that?
I don't care what others do.
Everyone lives by their own principles.
But look here.
What does it say in front of my name?
The Capital Garrison
Commander is not leaving the city.
Our unit will protect Seoul tonight.
Withdraw your command!
Are you ordering me?
I can't have my soldiers die
due to my superior's misjudgement.
Are you going to shoot?
Yes.
Shoot, if you've made up your mind.
You're a good commander.
If you think it's the right call
for your men, pull the trigger.
Stop!
Take one more step, and I'll shoot.
Do it quickly. I don't have time.
If not, come to the drill ground.
The rebels who abducted
the Army Chief of Staff
are now at the 30th Security.
They incited a rebellion
to seize state power.
Letting part of the CGC agree to it
makes me ashamed as commander.
But I can't tolerate this action
as a soldier of the Republic of Korea.
Tonight's going to be rough.
If you wish to leave, you may go now.
You're soldiers of the Shield
Corps, bearing CGC's honor and duty.
And as its commander,
I will subdue the rebels
with my brave soldiers.
Live to defend!
Die to serve!
Present arms!
Allegiance!
Allegiance.
They passed City Hall
and entered Sejongno.
Lee can jump into this war
because he has a cause.
- Jang!
- Yes, sir.
You stop those bastards,
and be sure not to fire first.
Yes, sir.
Move in combat formation.
All rebels in 30th Security, listen up.
I am CGC Commander Lee Tae-shin.
Disarm and surrender now.
You are soldiers of Korean Army
and under CGC's command.
I know better than anyone
you aren't here voluntarily.
It's not too late to
lay down your guns.
When's the 9th Division arriving?
It'll take more than 20 minutes.
They set off ages ago.
Tell them to come at full speed.
Hey, hurry up.
Push through them!
They're coming in.
Do not engage until they fire first.
Can you hear me?
I'm the Security Commander,
Chun Doo-gwang.
What on earth are you doing?
Can't you see you don't
stand a chance here?
Did you really think
you could threaten
us with only four tanks?
Colonel, this is your commander.
Report if you're ready to fire.
Target, 30th Security.
155mm high explosives,
one battery, three
rounds, ready to fire, sir.
Fix the firing point
to the 30th Security Group,
where the rebels are hiding.
Deflection angle 2, 5, 0, 5.
Tilt angle 3, 6, 4!
Fixed to the 30th Security!
Hey, is this for real?
Buy some time, I'll call the Artillery.
Unit at my command!
Tilt angle 3, 6, 4!
- Shell ready!
- Ready to fire!
Come on, Commander.
Are you really going
to burn down Seoul?
Stop this and come in for a minute.
I can explain all this.
You're not worth listening to.
Colonel Yoo!
On my command, strike with precision.
- "Precision"?
- That nutcase!
Hand me my gun.
General, how did this happen?
Just calm down, for fuck's sake!
I need to think, so just shut up!
Some CGC commanders
will be severely punished.
I'll go out and stop
him whatever it takes.
You take care of this place, okay?
Alright.
- Say something.
- Hey!
Colonel, the target
point has to be precise.
You do understand
what that means, right?
Commander.
Could you reconsider your order?
Target remains the 30th Security.
Yes, sir.
- I ask all of you officers.
- That prick.
Why do our men need to be sacrificed?
You take orders from me,
the Capital Garrison Commander.
Surrender now, and I won't
bring charges against you.
Here, sir.
All of you with Commander
Lee, listen carefully.
If you do anything dangerous,
I will engage in full-scale
war, and wipe all of you out!
In exactly 5 minutes,
the artillery will start firing.
If you fire on us,
where do you think
the shells will fall?
They'll fall on your
heads! Then, we'll all die!
Did you talk to the Artillery?
No, I can't reach him.
What should we do?
You have two minutes until we fire.
Sure!
Just fire it already!
That'll give the commies a
great chance to invade us!
All responsibility falls on you,
so brace yourself
before you start this!
I did that long ago.
When the firing begins, we'll attack!
- Understood?
- Yes, sir!
All gunners, stand fast!
That son of a bitch...
Where do you think you're going?
Hey, I'm about to burst
now. Should I pee here?
General Lee? This is
the Minister of Defense.
Hold your fire.
It's all over now.
General Lee Tae-shin.
Hold your fire!
Minister, why are you
using their channel?
Man, you have to talk this through.
Why do you want to shed blood?
Press him harder.
I just finished my conversation
with General Chun.
So, go back to Garrison
Command and stand by.
No.
I can't do that.
It's an order from the
Minister of Defense.
Say no more and turn back.
Minister!
Withdraw your order,
and order the entire army
to arrest Chun Doo-gwang.
Lee Tae-shin!
Are you giving me orders?
You think I'm your subordinate?
You listen.
As of this minute, you are
removed from command.
You know what that means?
You are nothing now!
Lee Tae-shin is not a
commander anymore!
He's been removed!
CGC troops, you heard
what the Minister said!
Lee, traitor to the Army,
now has no authority over CGC.
Effective immediately, Lee Tae-shin
is no longer CGC Commander!
2nd Airborne is here.
Halt!
- All gunners, stand fast!
- Stand fast!
Hold your positions.
Maintain formation.
Hey! Move those people!
Don't let civilians through.
- Jang.
- Yes, sir.
Let people come through.
- It's still dangerous here...
- Just do it.
Yes, sir.
Leave them!
Sir, there are civilians there.
Don't block the civilians!
How was it?
The Minister's timing was perfect.
Sir, it's the Chief of Artillery.
Commander, this is Colonel Yoo.
I'm sorry, sir.
I can't follow your orders anymore.
I... truly am.
Soldiers.
This is it. Thank you for your effort.
All of you,
I thank you for serving the
most useless commander of all.
Commander.
Return to base and let them rest.
You did very well.
General Lee made a brave decision!
CGC troops, listen carefully.
Lay down your arms,
and turn the engines off.
Sorry I couldn't serve you better.
Sorry, sir.
And if anyone is crazy enough
to defy me, I'll show no mercy!
Let me make one last
request as a commander.
Do not follow me.
Commander.
Look there, sir.
He's gone mad.
Chun Doo-gwang, you son of a bitch.
I won't let you go like this.
Can't we shoot him for
disobeying the Minister's order?
Give us permission to fire.
I'm ordering all CGC troops!
Lee Tae-shin is a war criminal.
Shoot him!
All troops, take aim.
Didn't you hear? Aim!
Target on mark.
We can't do this.
Too many eyes are on us.
Hands in the air, bastards!
You aren't worthy as a Korean soldier
or even a human being.
Sir, please come with me.
- Great job today.
- It's all over.
Don't laugh.
- Stop here for a second.
- Yes, sir.
What's wrong?
Go ahead first. You
tell them that we won.
- Go.
- Yes, sir.
- We are...
- One!
Sorry about earlier, sir.
Oh, it was nothing.
I did it for my country, too.
Have a drink.
- I can't drink.
- Please.
Seriously, I'm taking
tonics these days.
- Come on, drink it up.
- Oh, stop it.
Here comes our hero.
What are you doing? Come inside!
You did it.
We're still friends, right?
You fool, why even ask?
Take it.
Where are you going?
To piss.
Strip down naked.
Chief, are you in there?
Here's the authorization
letter for the arrest.
It's an ex post facto approval.
From now on,
we give our lives for our country,
the whole nation and its people.
For the Republic of Korea.
- We are one!
- One!
With a bamboo hat and
a cane, I wander the world
Let's continue.
Where's that bastard Chun?
Don't just stand there, come in.
You should sit here.
- Hee-chul.
- Yes.
Sit next to General Roh.
Chang-se, you come here.
Come closer so we can all fit.
Moon Il-pyung
Member of 14th, 15th National Assembly
Ha Chang-soo
Member of 14th National Assembly
Lim Hak-joo
Member of 13th National Assembly
Jang Min-gi
Director of National Security Planning
Jin Young-do
Army Chief of Staff
Kim Chang-se
Minister of Defense
Do Hee-chul
Army Chief of Staff
Bae Song-hak
Member of 12th, 13th, 14th National Assembly
Hyun Chi-sung
Minister of Transportation
Han Young-gu
11th, 12th Director of Board of Audit & Inspection
Roh Tae-gun
13th President of South Korea
Chun Doo-gwang
11th, 12th President of South Korea
Hanahoe took control of the military,
and tried to usurp the government.
In the spring of 1980, they
crushed student-led protests.
They sent Airborne troops to suppress
democratization in Gwangju.
In the end, they swallowed
up the nation as a whole.
Thus the radiant Seoul
Spring came to an end.